Register of the Wladyslaw Anders Collection, 1939-1946.
Hoover Institution Archives
- MATERIALS FILED BY DOCUMENT NUMBER
  - 3427/Og. tj/43 Placowka Nr. 1 (Outpost Nr. 1), November 5, 1943 (Folder 23)
  - 7563 Londyn - radiogram (London - radiogram), November 25, 1943 (Folder 24)
  - 132/tj/43 Biuro Dok. (Documents Bureau), December 13, 1943 (Folder 25)
  - 137/tj/43 Biuro Dok. (Documents Bureau), December 15, 1943 (Folder 26)
  - 14374/Inf. I/43 Dowodztwo APW (I/43 Polish Army in the East Headquarters), November 27, 1943 (Folder 27)
  - 133/tj/8 Biuro Dok. (Documents Bureau), December 7, 1943 (Folder 28)
  - 3498/tj/I D-ca Rejonu Teryt. Palestyna i Ofic. Laczn. Przy HQ Palest. (Commander of the Palestine Territorial Area and Liaison Officer at Palestine Headquaters), December 28, 1943 (Folder 29)
  - 976/tj/Cyw./43 Dowodztwo APW (Polish Army in the East Headquarters), December 29, 1943 (Folder 30)
  - 2/tj/44 Instrukcja w sprawie zbierania materjalow dotyczacych okupacji sowieckiej oraz Rosji sowieckiej (Instructions for collecting materials concerning the Soviet occupation and Soviet Russia) (Folder 31)
  - Rtm. Swiecicki Capt. Swiecicki), January 3, 1944 (Folder 32)
  - 291243 Depesza (telegram), December 29, 1943 (Folder 33)
  - 1034 Radiogram, December 31, 1943 (Folder 34)
  - 040144 Odpis depeszy (Copy of telegram), January 1, 1944 (Folder 35)
  - 188/44 Duszpasterstwo wyzn. mojzeszowego (Jewish clergy), January 7, 1944 (Folder 36)
  - 16a (Folder 37)
  - 220/Inf/I/tj/44 Dowodztwo APW (Polish Army in the East Headquarters), January 8, 1944 (Folder 38)
  - 020244 Notatka (Note), February 2, 1944 (Folder 39)
  - 53/tj Biuro Dokumentow (Documents Bureau), February 16, 1944 (Folder 40)
  - 225/tj/SD/44 Dowodztwo APW (Polish Army in the East Headquarters), February 4, 1944 (Folder 41)
  - 226/44 Duszpasterstwo wyzn. mojzeszowego (Jewish clergy), February 11, 1944 (Folder 42)
  - Biuro Dokumentow
    - 75/tj February 19, 1944 (Folder 43)
    - 82/tj/44 February 21, 1944 (Folder 44)
    - 86/tj/44 February 29, 1944 (Folder 45)
    - Notatka (Note), February 13, 1944 (Folder 46)
    - 93/tj/44 February 11, 1944 (Folder 47)
  - 220244 Exspozytura "T" (Section "T"), February 22, 1944 (Folder 48)
  - 1293/Wyw.tj/44 Naczelny wodz (Supreme Commander-in-Chief), February 16, 1944 (Folder 49)
  - Biuro Dokumentow
    - 133/tj/44 March 16, 1944 (Folder 50)
    - 138/tj/44 March 21, 1944 (Folder 51)
  - 100344 Regulamin wewnetrzny (Internal regulations), March 10, 1944 (Folder 52)
  - 98/tj/44 Dowodztwo APW - Wydzial Wywiadu Obronnego (Polish Army in the East Headquarters - Intelligence Section), March 20, 1944 (Folder 53)
  - Biuro Dokumentow
    - 149/tj/44 March 25, 1944 (Folder 54)
    - 163/tj/44 March 30, 1944 (Folder 55)
    - 173/tj/44 April 11, 1944 (Folder 56)
  - Odpis "dla wykonania uchwaly Rady Ministrow" (Copy "for the execution of the resolution of the Council of Ministers"), February 1944 (Folder 57)
  - 100444 Dowodca III/4 P.A.L. (Commander of III/4 P.A.L.), April 10, 1944 (Folder 58)
  - 98/tj/44 Samodzielny Referat Historyczny (Separate Historical Section), April 15, 1944 (Folder 59)
  - 210/tj/44 Biuro Dokumentow (Documents Bureau), May 8, 1944 (Folder 60)
  - 761/P1/9 Konsulat Generalny RP w Jerozolime (Polish Consulate General in Jerusalem), May 1, 1944 (Folder 61)
  - 217/tj/44 Biuro Dokumentow (Documents Bureau), May 12, 1944 (Folder 62)
  - 140/44 Placowka 5 (Outpost Nr. 5), April 2, 1944 (Folder 63)
  - Biuro Dokumentow (Documents Bureau)
    - 133/tj/44 March 16, 1944 (Folder 64)
    - Usuplnienie notatki (Supplement to an official note), June 6, 1944 (Folder 65)
    - 232/tj/44 June 1, 1944 (Folder 66)
    - 252a/tj/44 July 3, 1944 (Folder 67)
    - 260/tj/44 July 10, 1944 (Folder 68)
    - 260/tj/44 July 7, 1944 (Folder 69)
    - 1789/tj/44 July 7, 1944 (Folder 70)
    - 264/tj/44 July 12, 1944 (Folder 71)
    - 266/tj/44 August 11, 1944 (Folder 72)
    - 542/tj/Og.44 Plk Sadowski, July 26, 1944 (Folder 73)
  - 283/tj/44 Biuro Dokumentow (Documents Bureau), August 2, 1944 (Folder 74)
  - 040844 Naczelny wodz (Supreme Commander-in-Chief), August 4, 1944 (Folder 75)
  - 2246/tj/44 Ekspozytura "T" (Section "T"), August 12, 1944 (Folder 76)
  - Biuro Dokumentow (Documents Bureau)
    - 292/tj/44 August 14, 1944 (Folder 77)
    - 293/tj/44 August 22, 1944 (Folder 78)
    - 295/tj/44 August 26, 1944 (Folder 79)
  - 225 Dowodca 3 Korpusu (3rd Corps Commander), August 21, 1944 (Folder 80)
  - 303/tj/44 Biuro Dokumentow (Documents Bureau), September 1, 1944 (Folder 81)
  - Mjr. Bilewicz, August 12, 1944 (Folder 82)
  - Notaka sluzbowa (Official note), August 4, 1944 (Folder 83)
  - Biuro Dokumentow (Documents Bureau)
    - 324/tj/44 September 1944 (Folder 84)
    - 341/tj/44 September 22, 1944 (Folder 85)
    - 432/tj/44 September 22, 1944 (Folder 86)
    - 347/tj/44 September 27, 1944 (Folder 87)
    - Notatka sluzbowa (Official note), September 13, 1944 (Folder 88)
  - Zadania Biura Dokmentow (Documents Bureau functions) (Folder 89)
  - 242/tj/Kwat.Zaop/44 Dowodztwo 3 Korpusu (3rd Corps Headquarters), September 29, 1944 (Folder 90)
  - 150944 Projekt: rozkaz Dowodcy 3 Korpusu o organizacji Biura Dokumentow (Project: 3rd Corps Commander's order regarding the organization of the Documents Bureau), September 15, 1944 (Folder 91)
  - 95/44 Oddzial Opieki nad Zolnierzem 3-go Korpusu (3rd Corps Department of Soldier's Welfare), October 4, 1944 (Folder 92)
  - 360/tj/44 Biuro Dokumentow (Documents Bureau), September 29, 1944 (Folder 93)
  - 186/Adj. ZD/44 Zastepca Dowodcy 3 Korpusu (3rd Corps Deputy Commander), October 2, 1944 (Folder 94)
  - Biuro Dokumentow (Documents Bureau) (Box 78.)
    - 364/tj/44 October 7, 1944 (Folder 1)
    - 372/tj/44 October 10, 1944 (Folder 2)
  - 524/Kanc/tj/44 Dowodztwo 3 Korpusu (3rd Corps Headquarters), October 10, 1944 (Folder 3)
  - Biuro Dokumentow (Documents Bureau)
    - 377/tj/44 October 14, 1944 (Folder 4)
    - Notatka sluzbowa (Official note), November 6, 1944 (Folder 5)
    - 407/tj/44 November 7, 1944 (Folder 6)
  - Por. Malinowski - meldunek (report), November 27, 1944 (Folder 7)
  - 48/tj/44 Biuro Dokumentow (Documents Bureau), November 14, 1944 (Folder 8)
  - 271/Adj/tj/44 Dowodca 2 Korpusu (2nd Corps Commander), October 27, 1944 (Folder 9)
  - 419/tj/44 Biuro Dokumentow (Documents Bureau), November 7, 1944 (Folder 10)
  - 424/425/BD/tj/44 Dowodca 3 Korpusu (3rd Corps Commander), November 20, 1944 (Folder 11)
  - Biuro Dokumentow - notatka sluzbowa (Documents Bureau - official note), November 20, 1944 (Folder 12)
  - 433/BD/tj/44 Dowodca 3 Korpusu (3rd Corps Commander), November 23, 1944 (Folder 13)
  - 6126 Radiogram - London, November 23, 1944 (Folder 14)
  - Dowodztwo 3 Korpusu (3rd Corps Headquarters)
    - 448/BD/tj/44 November 5, 1944 (Folder 15)
    - 867/Op.Wyszk/44 December 9, 1944 (Folder 16)
    - 389/tj/Prop/44 October 5, 1944 (Folder 17)
  - Biuro Dokumentow (Documents Bureau)
    - 6/tj/45 January 5, 1945 (Folder 18)
    - Por. Malinowski, December 28, 1944 (Folder 19)
  - Dowodztwo Jednostek Wojska na Strodkowym Wschodzie (Military Units in the Middle East Headquarters)
    - 11/tj/Org/45 January 1945 (Folder 20)
    - 102/Pfn/Kanc/45 January 22, 1945 (Folder 21)
  - Biuro Dokumentow (Documents Bureau)
    - Notatka sluzbowa (Official note), February 2, 1945 (Folder 22)
    - 32/tj/45 February 7, 1945 (Folder 23)
    - 53/tj/45 February 20, 1945 (Folder 24)
  - 313/tjn/Pers/45 Dowodztwo Jednostek Wojska na Srodkowym Wschodzie (Military Units in the Middle East Headquarters), February 23, 1945 (Folder 25)
  - 83/tj/45 Biuro Dokumentow (Documents Bureau), May 15, 1945 (Folder 26)
  - 141/Org. Pers./tj/45 Oddzial Kultury i Prasy 2 Korpusu (2nd Corps Department of Culture and Press), May 7, 1945 (Folder 27)
  - Biuro Dokumentow (Documents Bureau)
    - 84/tj/45 May 5, 1945 (Folder 28)
    - 85/tj/45 May 7, 1945 (Folder 29)
  - 24/II tjn./Kwat.Ruch/45 Dowodztwo Jednostek Wojska na Srodkowym Wschodzie (Military Units in the Middle East Headquarters), March 22, 1945 (Folder 30)
  - Biuro Dokumentow (Documents Bureau)
    - 109/tj/45 May 18, 1945 (Folder 31)
    - 210445 Notatka sluzbowa (Official note), April 21, 1945 (Folder 32)
    - 240445 Notatka sluzbowa (Official note), April 24, 1945 (Folder 33)
  - 270445 Por. Podolski, April 27, 1945 (Folder 34)
  - 105a/tj/45 Biuro Dokumentow (Documents Bureau), April 1, 1945 (Folder 35)
  - 113/pr./tj/O.R./45 Oddzial Kultury i Prasy (Department of Culture and Press), April 19, 1945 (Folder 36)
  - Biuro Dokumentow (Documents Bureau)
    - 108/tj/45 May 14, 1945 (Folder 37)
    - 113/tj/45 May 24, 1945 (Folder 38)
  - 180645 Por. Podolski, June 18, 1945 (Folder 39)
  - Biuro Dokumentow (Documents Bureau)
    - 122/tj/45 May 29, 1945 (Folder 40)
    - 124/tj/45 June 1, 1945 (Folder 41)
  - 435/Og/tj/45 Oddzial Kultury i Prasy (Department of Culture and Press), June 11, 1945 (Folder 42)
  - Biuro Dokumentow (Documents Bureau)
    - 129/tj/45 June 13, 1945 (Folder 43)
    - 132/tj/45 June 13, 1945 (Folder 44)
    - 133/tj/45 June 15, 1945 (Folder 45)
    - 139/tj/45 June 26, 1945 (Folder 46)
    - 140/tj/45 July 3, 1945 (Folder 47)
    - 142/tj/45 July 6, 1945 (Folder 48)
  - Por. Podolski
    - 060745 Notatka (note), July 18, 1945 (Folder 49)
    - 180845 August 18, 1945 (Folder 50)
  - 157/tj/45 Biuro Dokumentow (Documents Bureau), August 28, 1945 (Folder 51)
  - 300745 Por. Bacciarelli, July 30, 1945 (Folder 52)
  - 271045 Biuro Dokumentow - Uwagi krytyczne o ksiazce red. J. Mackiewicza w sprawie Katynia (Documents Bureau - Critical remarks about the book edited by J. Mackiewicz conerning Katyn), October 27, 1945 (Folder 53)
  - 200/204/AG/tj Dowodztwo 2 Korpusu (2nd Cors Headquarters), November 10, 1945 (Folder 54)
  - Por. Podolski, November 28, 1945 (Folder 55)
  - Biuro Dokumentow (Documents Bureau)
    - 191/tj/45 December 4, 1945 (Folder 56)
    - 194/tj/45 December 13, 1945 (Folder 57)
    - 195/tj/45 December 12/13, 1945 (Folder 58)
  - 28L9/Op.H/45 Dowodztwo 2 Korpusu (2nd Corps Headquarters), December 13, 1945 (Folder 59)
  - 201/tj/45 Biuro Dokumentow (Documents Bureau), January 5, 1945 (Folder 60)
  - Oddzial Kultury i Prasy (Department of Culture and Press), n.d. (Folder 61)
  - Biuro Dokumentow (Documents Bureau)
    - 3/tj/45 January 11, 1946 (Folder 62)
    - Projekt rozkazu o organizacja Biuro Dokumentow (Draft of the order on the organization of the Documents Bureau), n.d. (Folder 63)
    - 9/tj/45 January 19, 1946 (Folder 64)
  - 20/BS/tj/46 Biuro Studiow (Studies Office), January 30, 1946 (Folder 65)
  - Biuro Dokumentow (Documents Bureau)
    - 19/tj/46 January 31, 1946 (Folder 66)
    - 23/tj/46 February 1946 (Folder 67)
    - 25/tj/46 March 1, 1946 (Folder 68)
  - Dowodztwo 2 Korpusu (2nd Corps Headquarters), February 14, 1946 (Folder 69)
  - Biuro Dokumentow (Documents Bureau)
    - 31/tj/46 February 28, 1946 (Folder 70)
    - 32/tj/46 February 28, 1946 (Folder 71)
    - 38/tj/46 March 26, 1946 (Folder 72)
  - 1465/Org.Pers./46 Oddzial Kultury i Prasy (Department of Culture and Press), April 5, 1946 (Folder 73)
  - Biuro Dokumentow (Documents Bureau)
    - 39/tj/46 March 20, 1946 (Folder 74)
    - 52/tj/46 April 29, 1946 (Folder 75)
    - 57/tj/46 May 4, 1946 (Folder 76)
  - 295/Org.Pers./46 Oddzial Kultury i Prasy (Department of Culture and Press), April 29, 1946 (Folder 77)
  - Biuro Dokumentow (Documents Bureau)
    - 59/tj/46 May 10, 1946 (Folder 78)
    - 65/tj/46 April 29, 1946 (Folder 79)
  - 915/Op.H./46 Dowdodztwo 2 Korpusu (2nd Corps Headquarters), May 24, 1946 (Folder 80)
  - 1390/ZR/46 Oddzial Kultury i Prasy (Department of Culture and Press), April 30, 1946 (Folder 81)
  - Garnizonowa Instrukcja Bezpieczenstwa (Instructions for Garrison Security), n.d. (Folder 82)
  - Biuro Dokumentow (Documents Bureau)
    - 77/tj/46 June 11, 1946 (Folder 83)
    - 83/tj/46 June 14, 1946 (Folder 84)
    - 87/tj/46 June 22, 1946 (Folder 85)
  - 708/Op/tj/46 Dowodztwo 2 Korpusu (2nd Corps Headquarters), April 8, 1946 (Folder 86)
  - Szef Sztabu Glownego (Chief of Staff Headquarters), April 29, 1946 (Folder 87)
  - Biuro Dokumentow (Documents Bureau)
    - 100/tj/46 June 12, 1946 (Folder 88)
    - 101/tj/46 July 26, 1946 (Folder 89)
    - 110/tj/46 August 21, 1946 (Folder 90)
    - 115/tj/46 August 21, 1946 (Folder 91)
  - 1256/tj/Op.H./46 Dowodztwo 2 Korpusu (2nd Corps Headquarters), August 16, 1946 (Folder 92)
  - 123/tj/46 Biuro Dokumentow (Documents Bureau), August 23, 1946 (Folder 93)
  - Dowodztwo 2 Korpusu - rozkaz tajny Nr. 18 (2nd Corps Headquarters - secret order No. 18), August 31, 1946 (Folder 94)
  - Biuro Dokumentow (Documents Bureau)
    - 147/tj/46 September 21, 1946 (Folder 95)
    - 158/tj/46 October 15, 1946 (Folder 96)
  - Dowodztwo 2 Korpusu (2nd Corps Headquarters) (Box 79.)
    - 1410/H/Pf/46 October 8, 1946 (Folder 1)
    - 1169/tj/SD/46 October 13, 1946 (Folder 2)
  - 763/Pers./tj/46 Oddzial Kultury i Prasy (Department of Culture and Press), October 10, 1946 (Folder 3)
  - Wyciag z depeszy (Excerpt from a telegram), October 21, 1946 (Folder 4)
  - Biuro Dokumentow (Documents Bureau)
    - 167/pf/46 October 24, 1946 (Folder 5)
    - 169/pf/46 October 26, 1946 (Folder 6)
  - 1169/tj/SD/46 Oddzial Sluzby Sztabu (Department of Staff Service), October 13, 1946 (Folder 7)
  - Dowodztwo 2 Korpusu (2nd Corps Headquarters)
    - 546/Kwat/tj October 15, 1946 (Folder 8)
    - 225/AG/46 October 25, 1946 (Folder 9)
    - 2374/Kwat. October 25, 1946 (Folder 10)
  - Biuro Dokumentow (Documents Bureau)
    - 193/tj/46 November 10, 1946 (Folder 11)
    - Notatka sluzbow (Official note), December 30, 1946 (Folder 12)
    - 197/tj/46 December 30, 1946 (Folder 13)
  - 2608/46 Zastepca Szefa Sztabu Glownego (Assistant Chief of Staff), December 19, 1946 (Folder 14)
- MISCELLANY, 1939-1945
  - Letters of Polish citizens in the Soviet Union, 1942 (Folder 15-19)
  - Letters of Polish citizens in the Soviet Union, 1942 (Box 80., Folder 1-3)
  - Polish 2nd Corps
    - Builetyn Doswiadczen Wojennych 2 Polskiego Korpusu (Bulletin of the Military Experience of the 2nd Polish Corps), June 1945 (Folder 4-5)
    - Instrukcja Dzialan w Gorach - Projekt (Instructions for Operations in the Mountains - A Plan), September 1943 (Folder 6)
    - Komisja Studiow (Studies Commission)
      - "Nauki z Dzialan we Wloszech" (Notes on Operations in Italy)
        - Nr. 12, March 1944 (Folder 7)
      - "Nauki z Dzialan we Wloszech" (Notes on Operations in Italy) (Contd.)
        - Nr. 14, September 1944 (Folder 8)
        - Nr. 15, April 1944 (Folder 9)
        - Nr. 19, July 1944 (Box 81., Folder 1)
      - "78 Dywizja w Dzialaniach Poscigowych" (78th Division in the Pursuit Battle), September 1944 (Folder 2)
      - Walki gorskie (Mountain battles), April 1944 (Folder 3)
      - Taktyka w Chwili Obecnej (Tactics at the Preset Time), January 1945 (Folder 4)
      - Wyzsza Szkola Wojenna, Podrecznik dla Prac Sztabow Wielkich Jednostek (Higher Military School, Manual for the Operations of Headquarters of Large Units)
        - Dane organizacyjne (Organizational data), April 1944 (Folder 5)
        - Taktyka sluzb (Tactics of services), April 1944 (Folder 6)
  - "Rok 1939 - Przyczyny Szybkiego Upadku Polski" (The Year of 1939 - Reasons for Poland's Fast Surrender) (Folder 7)
- EXCERPTS FROM STATEMENTS BY POLES IN THE SOVIET UNION, 1940-43 (Translated into English)
  - "DAR" (Folder 8-9)
  - "WA" (Folder 10)
  - Nos. 150000-150249 (Box 82., Folder 1-6)
  - Nos. 150250-150464 (Box 83., Folder 1-7)
  - Nos. 150465-150699 (Box 84., Folder 1-6)
  - Nos. 150700-150949 (Box 85., Folder 1-7)
  - Nos. 150950-151094 (Box 86., Folder 1-7)
  - Nos. 151095-151278 (Box 87., Folder 1-8)
- MICROFICHE COPIES OF DOCUMENTS
  - Microfiche Copies of Documents (Box 88.)
- SUBJECT INDEX TO DOCUMENTS
  - Subject Index to Documents (Box 89. - 92.)
- CARD INDEX OF NAMES OF POLES WHO DIED OR WERE LOST IN THE USSR
  - A - Bros (Box 93.)
  - Broz - Dombrowski (Box 94.)
  - Dombrowski - Gol
  - Gon - Jaroz (Box 96.)
  - Jarski - Kon (Box 97.)
  - Kop - Kz (Box 98.)
  - L - Marr (Box 99.)
  - Mars - Nied (Box 100.)
  - Niei - Pio (Box 101.)
  - Pip - R (Box 102.)
  - S - Suc (Box 103.)
  - Sud - T (Box 104.)
  - U - Zaj (Box 105.)
  - Zak - Zz (Box 106. - 107.)
- CARD INDEX OF NAMES AND LOCATIONS OF FORCED LABOR CAMPS IN THE USSR
  - A - U (Box 106. - 107.)
  - V - Z (Box 108. - 109.)
- CARD INDEX FOR FORCED LABOR CAMP TERMS, ABBREVIATIONS, LOCATIONS, SHIPS, AND PROFESSIONAL CATEGORIES OF INDIVIDUALS
- CARD INDEX TO REPORTS AND STATEMENTS
- GLASS PLATE NEGATIVES OF POLES IN THE USSR AND POLAND DURING WORLD WAR II
  - Glass Plate Negatives of Poles in the USSR and Poland during World War II (Box 110.)